RITU PANDE

Michigan United States

Email: ritz.pande@gmail.com

Profile

Technology principal, specializing in applied cryptography, public key infrastructure and security architecture for connected embedded devices. Experience in technically building and mentoring large teams to take a product/service from conceptualization/pre-sales to production.

I am also an independent researcher, collaborating with experts in academia. My research interests include:

- Graph Neural Networks
- Group Convolutions
- Self-Organizing Systems

For more information, please refer ritupande.github.io

Research Experience:

- Publications
 - Hierarchical Neural Cellular Automata,
 R Pande, D Grattarola
 Artificial Life Conference (ALife 2023) | Paper, Code, Talk
- Projects
 - Adaptive Traffic Signal Control using Deep Reinforcement Learning. Code
- Skills
 - Tensor Flow, Numpy, Python, Object Oriented Programming
 - Self-organizing systems, Neural Cellular Automata, Deep Learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning, Graph Neural Networks
- Certifications.
 - Natural Language Processing Specialization
 - AI for Medicine
 - Mathematics for Machine Learning
 - Deep Learning Specialization
 - Reinforcement Learning Specialization
- More info: ritupande.qithub.io

Professional Experience:

Employment

Company	Designation	Duration
General Motors	Software Architect, Technology Lead	Oct 2014 – Till date
Capgemini Group/ Altran Group/ Aricent Technologies/ Hughes Software Systems	 Director Technology Principal Systems Engineer Senior Technical Lead Technical Lead Senior Software Engineer 	July 2004 - Oct 2021
Wipro Technologies	Software Engineer	Oct 2002-July 2004
Innodata Information		
Technologies	System Engineer	Aug 2001 - Sept-2002

Skills

- Security architecture for embedded devices, applied cryptography, Public Key Infrastructure, Platform Security, Transport Layer Security, Android Security, Trusted Execution Environment, Secure Programming, Secured Onboard Communication.
- Automotive Network Architecture, CAN, SOME/IP, Vehicle Power Management, IP Transport, L2/L3 Switching
- Creating technical proposals detailing solutions to customer requirements and effectively presenting them.
- Architecting software for hypervisor-based virtualization environment.
- Programming Languages: C, object-oriented Python
- Tools: Jira, Github, Enterprise Architect
- Operation Systems: Linux, QNX
- Standards: X.509, IKEv2, IPsec, TLSv2, SHE, TrustZone
- Excellent verbal and oral communication skills

Recent Projects

General Motors connected car infotainment (2014- Till Date).

Lead Security Architect responsible for:

- Authoring PKI specification for all connected automotive ECUs capturing procurement, renewal and revocation strategy of device end-entity certificates.
- Authoring Secured Onboard Communication (SecOC) specification for automotive infotainment ECU.
- Authoring specification for flexible key provisioning for automotive infotainment ECU at plant and assembly.
- Designing strategy for integration of automotive ECU key store with trusted applications in Qualcomm Trusted Execution Environment.
- Designing ECU trusted certificate store strategy.
- Designing integration of GM developed security components with the communication protocol stacks (SOME/IP, TLS) in the ECU OS.
- Mentoring and training implementation teams on security and applied cryptography fundamentals.
- Leading end-to-end integration of the security features between connected infotainment ECU and the back-end servers.
- Threat modelling for attack vectors on automotive connected ECUs.

Lead Power and State Management Architect, responsible for:

- Authoring specification for power and state management for automotive infotainment ECU
- Technically leading implementation teams within General Motors and Tier-I suppliers to implement the power and state management functionality across SoC and Vehicle Interface Processor in automotive infotainment ECU.
- o Leading overall architecture integrating of power, thermal and voltage management
- Spearheading triaging and execution
- $\circ\quad$ Triaging vehicle manufacturing and assembly issues in the SW domain.
- Nokia Siemens Network(NSN) Femto Access Point (FAP) (2013- 2014)

Project Technical lead for the design and execution of security solution in FAP device.

o Designing the Trusted Execution Environment strategy in FAP using ARM Trustzone

- architecture.
- Technically leading the porting and integration of Aricent developed LTE stacks on SoC vendor's (Broadcom) BSP.
- Designing and leading execution of integration and optimization strategy of ciphering at LTE air interface with SoC provided HW accelerators.
- Leading the integration of encryption in the IPSec layer of Linux kernel with SoC provided HW accelerators.
- Technically leading the design and execution of integration of Strongswan Internet Key Exchange version 2 (IKEv2) stack on Linux operating system with FAP fast path.
- o Designing and leading execution of secure boot strategy for FAP
- Leading the execution of strategy for secure over-the-air download and subsequent flashing of firmware.
- o Designing the IP filter rules for implementing NATing in the FAP device.
- Nokia Siemens Network (NSN) Flexi-Edge Base Transceiver Station (BTS) (2009-2013)

Feature Lead for design and execution of security and transport solutions for the Base Transceiver Station

- Technically leading the design and execution of integration of Strongswan Internet Key Exchange version 2 (IKEv2) stack on QNX operating system with fast path executed in network processor.
- Technically leading the architecture, design and execution of CLM strategy for procurement, renewal and revocation of device end-entity certificates in the BTS

Leadership Experience:

- Experience in leading technical task force across multiple tier-1 suppliers and OEM teams to bring product features to fruition from their concept inception to deployment.
- Extensive experience in technically building and mentoring large teams (largest team size being 45) in the area of IP transport, security and layer 2 switching and routing strategies.
- Deft at providing technical leadership across parallel projects, resolving interface issues across multiple subsystems.

Teaching Experience:

- Aricent Technologies: Organizational trainer for 'Debugging Skills'.
- General Motors: Organizational trainer for 'Security and Applied Cryptography Fundamentals'.

Educational Qualifications:

Bachelor of Information Tech. Indraprastha College, Delhi University, India.

Awards and Achievements:

- Certificate of Merit in National Mathematics Olympiad competition, 1995
- Individual Employee Excellence award, Altran Group, 2008

Extra-Curricular Achievements:

- 1st Degree Black Belt holder in ITF Tae-kwon-do
- 1 Gold and 1 Silver in South Asian Tae-kwon-do Championships (ITF), Dec 2008
- 2 Gold and 1 Silver in National Tae-kwon-do Championships, Dec 2006

• Completed Airtel Delhi Half Marathon ' 09 and '10

I hereby agree that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Ritu Pande